


















    
        
    

    
        
    











    


<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"  xml:lang="en"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

        
            <copyright>© Nathan Hartley</copyright>
        

        <description>Recent content</description>

        
            <language>en</language>
        

        
            <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 22:26:12 BST</lastBuildDate>
        

        <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>

        

        <title></title>

        

        
            <item>
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                

                

                

                

                

                
                

                

                
                    
                

                

                

                

                
                    <description><![CDATA[<p>In November 2023, Voyager 1 started to send back non-coherent information to Earth after operating in space for over 46 years.</p>
<p>The spacecraft was designed with the primary goal of conducting close-up studies of Jupiter and Saturn in a five-year mission. Since it&rsquo;s <a href="https://voyager.jpl.nasa.gov/mission/status/">launch in September 1977</a>, it has travelled over 15 billion miles away from Earth in Interstellar space and is estimated to travel over 38,000 mph.</p>
<p><a href="https://voyager.jpl.nasa.gov/">NASA&rsquo;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL)</a>, which makes and operates the agency&rsquo;s robotic spacecraft, set out to fix Voyager 1 and return it to its original state. Other than it sending back gibberish data, it was still receiving commands and otherwise operating normally. An issue was found with one of the spacecraft&rsquo;s three onboard computers known as the flight data subsystem (FDS). The <a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/voyager/2024/04/04/engineers-pinpoint-cause-of-voyager-1-issue-are-working-on-solution/">team discovered</a> a single chip responsible for storing a portion of the FDS&rsquo;s memory has become faulty. Unable to repair this faulty chip, the team instead relocated the corrupted code elsewhere within the FDS.</p>
<p>After working for 5 months to repair the connection, with it taking 22.5 hours to send a signal to the spacecraft, a connection with Voyager 1 was finally re-established in April 2024! Thanks to NASA&rsquo;s JPL, the twin Voyager spacecrafts are still the <a href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasas-voyager-1-resumes-sending-engineering-updates-to-earth">longest-running and most distant spacecraft</a> in history.</p>
<p>Did you know that Voyager 1 holds the <a href="https://voyager.jpl.nasa.gov/galleries/making-of-the-golden-record/">Golden Record</a>?</p>
<p>Searching <a href="https://g.co/kgs/HT8aZUK">&lsquo;Voyager 1&rsquo;</a> or <a href="https://g.co/kgs/HT8aZUK">&lsquo;Voyager Program&rsquo;</a> into Google returns an interactive diagram of the spacecraft from NASA that displays all of its components and instruments. You can even test you knowledge to see how many components you can correctly identify. Give it a try!</p>
<p><img alt="Alt text" src="https://c02.purpledshub.com/uploads/sites/48/2020/08/Voyager-ee07727-scaled.jpg?w=1175&webp=1" title="Voyager 1"></p>
]]></description>
                

                <guid  isPermaLink="false" >tag:localhost:1313,2024-05-25:2024-05-25T22:26:12+01:00</guid>

                
                    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/voyager1/</link>
                

                
                    <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 22:26:12 BST</pubDate>
                

                
                    <title>Voyager 1 is still alive!</title>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                

                

                

                

                

                
                

                

                
                    
                

                

                

                

                
                    <description><![CDATA[<p>Hi, my name is <strong>Nathan</strong>.<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p>This is the first post on my <em>new</em> <a href="https://nhartley.dev/">website</a>.</p>
]]></description>
                

                <guid  isPermaLink="false" >tag:localhost:1313,2024-04-28:2024-04-28T16:43:12+01:00</guid>

                
                    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
                

                
                    <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 16:43:12 BST</pubDate>
                

                
                    <title>First Post</title>
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
